The flavor you know. The story you don't.
Flamin' Hot is a drama, history film directed by Eva Longoria.
The inspiring true story of Richard Montañez, the Frito Lay janitor who channeled his Mexican American heritage and upbringing to turn
the iconic Flamin' Hot Cheetos into a snack that disrupted the food industry and became a global pop culture phenomenon.
Richard Montañez, played by Jesse García.
Judy Montañez, played by Annie Gonzalez.
Vacho Montañez, played by Emilio Rivera.
Concha Montañez, played by Vanessa Martinez.
Clarence C. Baker, played by Dennis Haysbert.
Roger Enrico, played by Tony Shalhoub.
Flamin' Hot is a 2023 American biographical comedy-drama film directed
by Eva Longoria in her feature-length directorial debut.
Written by Linda Yvette Chávez and Lewis Colick, it is based on the memoir A Boy, a Burrito and a Cookie:
From Janitor to Executive by Richard Montañez, who claims to have invented Flamin' Hot Cheetos.
The film stars Jesse Garcia, Annie Gonzalez, Dennis Haysbert, and Tony Shalhoub.
The film had its world premiere at South by Southwest on March 11, 2023.
It was released on June 9, 2023, by Hulu and
Disney+ to mixed reviews from critics.
At the 96th Academy Awards, Flamin' Hot received a nomination for Best Original Song for "The Fire
Inside" written by Diane Warren, but lost to “What Was I Made For?” from Barbie.
The film explores themes of biography, based on true story,
janitor, mexican american, woman director.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.